Guide to the William A. Graham Collection of Television Scripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William A. Graham collection of television scripts
1955-1968
YCAL MSS 482
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
12.3
(30 boxes)
The William A. Graham collection of television scripts contains scripts and other material for American television anthology series and other programs from the mid 1950s through late 1960s.
Graham, William A., 1926-2013
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. William A. Graham.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
William A. Graham
William A. Graham, born in 1926, was an American director of television programs and films for nearly five decades, from the mid 1950s until 2002. He directed programs for a number of popular anthology series in the 1950s and 1960s and then directed movies for television.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains scripts and other material for American television anthology series and other programs from the mid 1950s through late 1960s. Popular live drama series during the Golden Age of Television included Kraft Television Theatre and its successors, Sunday Showcase, Studio One, United States Steel Hour, Playhouse 90, and others. Some programs, such as U.S. Steel Hour, originated as radio programs in the 1940s, and the scripts are based on adaptations of radio plays, adaptations from novels and other works, and original scripts for television. There are also scripts for feature-length films from the late 1960s and other programs. In addition to scripts, some folders contain documents, correspondence, photographs, and clippings.
Arrangement
Organized by television series.
Live television programs -- United States; Motion picture producers and directors; Television plays; Television plays, American; Television scripts; Photographic prints; Directors; Graham, William A., 1926-2013; Kraft Foods Company; United States Steel Corporation
- Scripts
  - Kraft Televesion Theatre
    - "All Those Beautiful Girls", 1957 May 24 (Box 1)
    - "Barefoot Soldier", 1957 September 27 (Box 1)
    - "The Battle for Wednesday Night", 1957 December 27 (Box 1)
    - "Bedroom 12 on the Appalachian Waterfall", 1956 May 23 (Box 1)
    - "The Braveness of Christy Fallon", 1955 May 18 (Box 1)
    - "The Category Is Murder", 1957 October 21 (Box 1)
    - "Come to Me", 1957 December 4 (Box 1)
    - "Day of Judgement", 1955 November 15 (Box 2)
    - "The Day of the Hunter", 1956 November 21 (Box 2)
    - "Eddie", 1958 (Box 2)
    - "The Girl Who Saw Too Much", 1956 August 29 (Box 2)
    - "Give Me the Courage", 1957 February 5 (Box 2)
    - "Hit and Run", 1956 October 17 (Box 2)
    - "Home Is the Hero", 1956 January 25 (Box 3)
    - "A Matter of Life", 1957 April 17 (Box 3)
    - "The Mob", 1955 June 29 (Box 3)
    - "The Old Ticker", 1957 September 11 (Box 3)
    - "Out to Kill", 1956 September 19 (Box 3)
    - "Paper Foxhole", 1956 April 4 (Box 3)
    - "Sextuplets!", 1957 August 7 (Box 4)
    - "Someone to Hang", 1955 June 8 (Box 4)
    - "Teddy Bear", 1956 December 12 (Box 4)
    - "Two Times Two", 1955 August 10 (Box 4)
    - "The Woman at High Hollow", 1958 February 26 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Mystery Theatre
    - "Cop Killer", 1958; 2 (Box 5)
  - Kraft Suspense Theatre
    - "The Hunt", 1963 August 5 (Box 5)
  - Pond's Theatre
    - "The Glass Parlor", 1955 April 7 (Box 5)
    - "A Second Chance", 1955 February 24 (Box 5)
    - "The Silver Box", 1955 March 17 (Box 5)
  - Sunday Showcase
    - "Hollywood Sings", 1960 March 31 (Box 5)
    - "The Light in the Dark", 1959 November 12 (Box 5)
    - "One Loud Clear Voice", 1960 January 4 (Box 6)
    - "The Poison-Bait Trappers", 1958 February 21 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous
    - "The Dentist Stood Pat", undated (Box 6)
    - "Let There Be Light", 1964 December 24 (Box 6)
    - "Sawdust on the Sidewalk", undated (Box 6)
    - "The Sea Monks", 1965 March 19 (Box 6)
  - Deadline
    - "One Tall, One Short", 1959 August 27 (Box 6)
    - "The Two Ounce Trap", 1959 August 12 (Box 6)
  - Dow Hour of Great Mysteries
    - "The Cat and the Canary", 1960 August 11 (Box 6)
  - Feature Films
    - "The Doomsday Flight", 1966; 3 (Box 7)
    - "The League of Frightened Men", 1967 May 1 (Box 7)
    - "The Revolution of Antonio De Leon", 1968 February 13 (Box 7)
    - "Trial Run", 1968; 2 (Box 7)
    - "Waterhole No. 3", 1966 May 19 (Box 7)
    - "Waterhole No. 3", 1966; 2 (Box 8)
  - United States Steel Hour
    - "The Imposter", 1960 February 25 (Box 8)
    - "The Investigator #1", 1958 May; 2 (Box 8)
    - "The Investigator #2", 1958 May 28; 2 (Box 8)
    - "The Investigator #4", 1958 June 10 (Box 8)
    - "The Investigator #7", 1958 July 14 (Box 9)
  - Rexall Special
    - "Swiss Family Robinson", 1958 June 6 (Box 9)
  - Avco Special
    - "Space - Man's Last Frontier", 1959 May; 2 (Box 9)
  - Special
    - "Bernstein in Berlin", 1960 September 20 (Box 9)
    - "Bernstein - Jazz in Serious Music", 1959 January 19 (Box 9)
    - "Bernstein - Romanticism in Music", 1961 January 13 (Box 9)
  - Special - Social Work
    - "Investment in Life", undated (Box 9)
  - Pay T.V. Special
    - "Show Girl" with Carol Channing, 1961 April 2 (Box 9)
  - Purex Special
    - "The Single Woman", 1960 December 28 (Box 9)
  - Special
    - "Sol Hurok Presents", 1967 December 8 (Box 10)
    - "The Sound of the Sixties", undated (Box 10)
  - Omnibus
    - "Dancing - A Man's Game", 1958 December 21 (Box 10)
    - "H.M.S. Pinafore" - Gilbert & Sullivan, 1959 May 10 (Box 10)
    - "The Strange Ordeal of the Normandier", 1959 April 12; 3 (Box 10)
  - Special - population explosion
    - "The People Trap", 1966 July 9 (Box 10)
  - Pilot
    - "And Then Came Bronson", 1968 October 31 (Box 11)
  - Pilot - The Insider
    - "Operation Hot Rock", 1965 December 3 (Box 11)
  - Pilot Film
    - "Three for Danger", undated (Box 11)
  - T.V. Pilot
    - "The Witness", 1960 September; 2 (Box 11)
  - T.V. Series
    - "The Eleventh Hour", 1963 March 15; 2 (Box 11)
    - "The Fugitive", 1963-1964; 3 (Box 11)
    - "Naked City", 1962-1963; 2 (Box 12)
    - "Twelve O'Clock High", 1965 February; 2 (Box 12)
  - Studio One
    - "24 Hours to Dawn", 1957 November 11 (Box 12)
    - "Please Report Any Odd Characters", 1957 November 18; 3 (Box 12)
    - "Escape Route", undated (Box 12)
    - "Escape Route", 1957; 2 (Box 13)
    - "Pathology" (working title), undated; 3 (Box 13)
    - "Pathology" (working title), undated; 2 (Box 14)
  - Brenner productions
    - #26, undated (Box 14)
    - #25, 1959 (Box 14)
    - #24, 1959 (Box 14)
    - #23, 1959 (Box 15)
    - #22, 1959 (Box 15)
    - #21, 1959 (Box 15)
    - #20, 1959 (Box 15)
    - #19, 1959 (Box 15)
    - #18, 1959 (Box 16)
    - #17, 1959 (Box 16)
    - #16, 1959 (Box 16)
    - #15, 1959 (Box 16)
    - #14, 1959 (Box 16)
    - #13, 1959 (Box 16)
    - #12, 1959 (Box 17)
    - #11, 1959 (Box 17)
    - #10, 1959 (Box 17)
    - #9, 1959 (Box 17)
    - #8, 1959 (Box 17)
    - #7, 1959 (Box 18)
    - #6, 1959 (Box 18)
    - #5, 1959 (Box 18)
    - #4, 1959 (Box 18)
    - #3, 1959 (Box 18)
    - #2, 1959 (Box 19)
    - #1, 1959 (Box 19)
    - Photographs of pilot set, undated (Box 19)
  - Playhouse 90
    - "Shadows Tremble", 1958 October 23 (Box 19)
    - "The Silver Whistle", 1959 December 14 (Box 19)
    - "The Blue Men", 1959 January 15 (Box 20)
    - "The Velvet Alley", 1959 January 22 (Box 20)
    - "A Quiet Game of Cards", 1959 January 29 (Box 20)
    - "Child of Our Time", 1959 February 5 (Box 20)
    - "The Second Man", 1959 February 12 (Box 21)
    - "The Raider", 1959 February 19 (Box 21)
    - "Made in Japan", 1959 March 5 (Box 21)
    - "Trip to Paradise", 1959 March 26 (Box 22)
    - "In Lonely Expectation", 1959 April 2 (Box 22)
    - "Day Before Atlanta", 1959 April 9 (Box 22)
    - "Judgement at Nuremberg", 1959 April 16 (Box 23)
    - "Diary of a Nurse", 1959 May 7 (Box 23)
    - "Marriage of Strangers", 1959 May 14 (Box 23)
    - "Out of Dust", 1959 May 21 (Box 23)
    - "Rank and File", 1959 May 28 (Box 24)
    - "To the Sound of Trumpets", 1960 February 9 (Box 24)
    - "The Cruel Day", 1960 February 24 (Box 24)
    - "Tomorrow", 1960; 2 (Box 24)
    - "Tomorrow, 1960 March 7 (Box 25)
    - "The Hiding Place", 1960 March 22 (Box 25)
  - Other scripts
    - "The Hollywood Complex", 1957; 5 (Box 25)
    - "The Defender Parts I & II", 1957; 4 (Box 26)
    - "A Child is Waiting", 1957 March 11; 2 (Box 26)
    - "A Child is Waiting", 1956-1957; 3 (Box 27)
    - "Walk Down the Hill", 1957; 5 (Box 27)
    - "A Member of the Family", 1957 (Box 27)
    - "A Member of the Family", 1957; 3 (Box 28)
    - "The Years in Between", 1957; 4 (Box 28)
    - "The Playwright and the Star", 1957; 3 (Box 28)
    - "The Playwright and the Star", undated (Box 29)
    - "The Rice Sprout Song", 1957; 5 (Box 29)
    - "The Traveling Lady", 1957; 4 (Box 29)
    - "The Deaf Heart", 1957 October 21 (Box 29)
    - "The Bend in the Road", 1957 November 4; 2 (Box 30)